the final event of the diving pool is
the men's 10 metre platform competition
one of the blue-ribbon events of the
whole games a spectacular combination of
artistry athleticism and sheer courage
it's a long journey to the medals podium
though 32 divers are in the pool for
tonight's preliminary round only 18 will
survive to make it into tomorrow
morning's semi-final the top 12 from
there we'll go forward to tomorrow night
to compete for gold expect the
atmosphere to hit fever pitch tonight
because Great Britain's poster boy Tom
Daley begins his personal quest for
glory having missed out on a medal in
the 10 metre synchro competition and he
and Peter Waterfield finished just out
of the frame in fourth place the Brits
are in action tonight and they brought
their support as ever but the world's
best are all in the lineup here two
Olympic champions two world champions
the Chinese have dominated in a diving
pool again but Russia's Ilya Zakharov
who won at gold at 3 meters as we look
at Tom Daley and Peter Waterfield
they're they're the ones getting the
cheers
well that Russian has proved the Chinese
are not completely unbeatable indeed 10
meters it's supposed to be the Chinese
team's most vulnerable event mind you
there's only one gold in three of the
last five Olympic Games we'll explain
the scoring and some of the more
technical aspects as we go along but the
important thing here is just to enjoy a
great show Steve for Billy Otis
alongside me looking to do just that as
well Steve you smell a lot of these
games covering the gymnastics and many
many ways is this what these guys are
they're gymnasts well they are really
and that you're going to see a lot of
the skills from gymnastics transfer
across to the 10-meter platform they've
only got three seconds though to get it
down from platform to water or even a
little less than that and six dives each
in what is quite a lengthy session for
them and as you mentioned Roger it's a
little bit of a marathon effort to get
yourself from these preliminaries into
the final and so they don't want to
start poorly it's in that respect it's
also like the gymnastics you have a
major qualifying day which
allows you to progress to a number of
other events in this case it's the you
know platform on through to the
semi-final to the final and we wish them
all well and we wish them safe
competition because that is a long way
up and some of the competitors will tell
you themselves they don't know why they
do it and they very aware of the danger
but it also makes for spectacular sport
they hit the water at speeds in excess
of 30 miles per hour so get it wrong and
getting it wrong is the big pressure of
course Steve because again like the
gymnasts and wahla to these artistic
sports that you cannot afford to get a
dive wrong because it could be game over
and with your first dive there's always
that pressure and no matter how
experienced you might be and live
galperin will go up first at 27 year old
russian and he's seen it all done it all
been out for a spell with injuries like
many of them have but to be the very
first competitor up brings its own
pressure but it won't be unfamiliar to
most of these leads who come to this
level of competition only because
they're very very good 6 dives each
tonight each dive has an agreed degree
of difficulty 7 judges who mark each
dive out of 10 the highest and lowest
two marks are discounted then the
remaining total is multiplied by the
degree of difficulty or the tariff that
is given to each dive sounds complicated
the captions you'll see come out the
graphics they will make it very clear
which marks are counting so don't worry
too much about any technicalities just
enjoy the show as we've said because the
action here can be spectacular 11 of
these divers plus one more have already
been in action in the synchronized
swimming which at least gives them a
feel of the pool but for most of them
it's been a long long wait to get there
Olympic Games underway quite a warm
evening and we're sitting up towards the
top of the venue where the warm air is
settling and we certainly feeling it but
I wouldn't mind a dip in their pool
myself but I don't think they're gonna
let us down there Roger
unfortunately not you'll see this just a
little bit of a glaze across the top of
the pool they put a spray on top of it
because when the divers are coming down
it gets rid of that mirror effect and
they can actually judge the distance
they are from the water I mean it's
frightening to think all that it's going
through their mind they tend to pick a
spot on the the ceiling on the outside
to use as a rotation point to orientate
themselves around for those of us who
don't do this sport we don't know how
they do it really no thanks no a lot of
courage serious amount of training and
work in the gym and a bit of work
between the ears as well to convince
yourself through how it should be done
and that should it be done at all that
we've galperin first of all one of the
most experienced competitors in the
competition the dives will get more
difficult as they go along in good three
and a half somersault over the three
point two tariffs and always so pleased
to get that first one out of the way and
it looked like he did a very good job in
tight to the platform that's part of the
danger of course and hit the water nice
and vertically and the good scores
coming in for him than 88 to start with
and four scores rejected as Rogers
explained to you the top two and bottom
299 a half's are excellent stuff this is
Lin UA who's one of the two Chinese
divers he was the 2008 Olympic synchro
champion competing this time
individually in with three and a half
somersault tucked position
just managed to fold it in underneath
the water make that little somersault
beneath so try and get those shins
vertical a nice tight tuck position and
gets through those somersaults early so
we can spot the water plenty of nines
coming the way of linear and they try
and drag those bubbles down with them to
create the best possible entry and least
possible splash you'll see them on the
way down the the replays which I should
emphasize the judges don't see those
replays we do you do but the judges have
to get their judgment right in one go
Victor Ortega from Colombia his second
Olympic Games and he kicks off for the
back two and a half somersault one and a
half twist piked
we just rolled that one over with his
feet and that's a little error that the
judges never miss certainly seem to get
through the twisting okay spots the
water now and those feet just roll over
so no chance of nines there judges are
looking for that tightness in either the
tucked all the Pike's position just how
close you can get your torso to the
thighs and really bunched up there so
he's giving up a few points to the early
divers already but the chances to make
them up of course with this long first
session anton zakharov from ukraine next
to go not to be confused with Ilya
Zakharov from Russia who won the synchro
competition in with three and a half
somersault tucked
popular starting dive and it gives you a
chance at home to compare how well it's
performed closeness to the board is just
unnerving at times isn't it yeah you
know and I don't think he he was still a
little bent at the hips as he entered
the water so wasn't quite vertical
hadn't quite come out of it a little
concern there I think for how tidy was
to the platform
72 for Sakharov Timofey older chick from
Belarus 10th in the World Championships
in Shanghai in 2011 is his best
performance to date back to an a half
somersault won the half-twist point
maybe just slightly under rotating as he
hit the water as opposed to Ortega who
overcooked it a little bit of a loss of
leg form there as the ankles came apart
so it sounds to like the judges have
spotted what we have if the ankles just
couldn't quite lock themselves together
and actually came apart twice so 72
he owned Jewry from the Democratic
People's Republic of Korea just 16 years
of age there's a lot of teenagers in
this competition as well
for with three and a half somersaults
galperin sir 88 is still standing at the
moment but we're expecting the Chinese
competitors here to do a wonderful job
it's so graceful and you see that he's
absolutely ripped that entry is barely a
splash drags all the bubbles down with
him two eight seven eight and a half
there this is Jimmy Connor from
Australia 17 years of age from Melbourne
lives in Brisbane trains there he's just
rolled the feet over there he won't be
too pleased with that first effort he
was the youngest in the Australian team
at the Delhi Commonwealth Games with
just 15 come to the top quickly and
early perhaps his best opening dive and
as the sevens come in he's entitle to be
nervous
frightening Lee young some of these
competitors quite an age range right up
into the the early 30s and I Peter
Waterfield from Great Britain and the
more senior divers in the whole
competition down to 15 and 16 year old
young boys really Martin Wolfram he's
aged 20 from Germany arm stand back
double somersault two and a half twists
an ambitious opening dive he's armed
stand positions are really hearty in
mouth for all of us watching high
tariffs to start off with the 3.6 see if
he can cash in
now okay and consider the degree of
difficulty is going to help him but the
execution not perfect the lower tariff
dives have got to be executed absolutely
spot-on you a little bit more margin for
error
on the higher more difficult dives but
obviously they want to cash in don't
think yeah and a different sort of error
they wasn't quite square to the water
his feet were twisted an ankle certainly
together and that again should be an
error that the judges can catch a first
look a first an only look in Claire
Aggie era from Cuba second Olympic Games
aged 22 another forward three and a half
somersault well he crashed into the
water really that was hardly miserable
in the era as on the entry knees a
little bent in the pike position there's
a few problems here for him he wasn't
square and it is the errors that the
judges are looking for we we certainly
don't mean to sound negative about these
great divers though at the Olympics
because they're the world's best but
when we're trying to reflect that the
thoughts of the judges here and the 61
five is a that's the lowest so far so he
had a few problems next up is Alexander
Bondar from the Ukraine he was already
competed in the synchro competition with
Alexander course covers off finished
eighth in with three and a half
somersault to begin his routine
well very tidy should do well here bond
are not too many identifiable problems
to his opening dive some of the Eastern
European divers are a little bit more
powerfully built which does tend to give
a different impression they're almost
more muscular divers than some of the
Chinese divers who were so incredibly
slight and whippy through the air I
think yes and there there's less mass
entering the water gives the Chinese
divers a better entry quite often but
the powerful men can certainly get the
job done in a different way
Jihu Park from Korea
thank you sir just rolling over a little
for park out of Busan in Korea had a
successful Asian Games its third in the
synchro 3-meter springboard and 72
equals seventh best mark they take a
long time for these positions to really
make a huge amount of sense with 32
divers to to get through really a
question of them getting this evening
out the way making no mistakes getting a
feel for the competition and maybe at
the top end laying down the odd marker
if you're amongst those with high
aspirations Victor mini bias from Russia
sixth in the 10 metre synchro as well in
with three and a half somersault tucked
well he was there a long time and I
wonder if there were a few stray
thoughts entering his mind
and if the execution was solid until he
kicked out for the entry and it was just
caught a bit short so that large splash
is such a giveaway a little bit of a
split in the tuck position most of the
divers have that it doesn't this upset
the judges too much they really only see
that from sidon but many buy of has paid
a penalty for the entry for sure I get
the right push off as well to get
through the rotations in time to unwind
to give themselves the chance of the
clean entry there's no spring on that
obviously it's all comes from the their
own push off and their own technique
German Sanchez from Mexico silver
medalist of the 10 metre synchro Mexico
who had a decent games the diving pool
such a strong nation in this sport
Mexico or nice the crowd really
appreciated that entry there their
instant experts like like everyone at
home but you learn to pick a good dive
don't you in the the entry is such an
important impression to leave they call
it the RIP don't then you can hear that
different sound
he's only 47 K that seven stone six was
on the lightest going and really the
spin speed there in his rotations and
he's earnt the top mark so far galperin
the first diver was leading for quite a
time there with 88 but now eighty nine
point one for German Sanchez and his
strong performance in the synchro would
serve up his confidence and confidence
as in all sports but this in particular
is massive and you can understand why
from that formidable height Rowley
McCormick from Canada
again a very nice entry of from Riley
his second Olympics he didn't make the
final in Beijing finished 16th so his
first aim will be to not just get
through tonight but tomorrow morning and
being the father would be good for him
he'll turn 21 in a couple of weeks and
has made a very solid start here 73.5
leaves him in equals seventh position
and there are lots of interest about our
next competitor yep one of the stars of
the show the superstar from Beijing
Matthew Mitchum he is a big man is me
well he's a big star in Australia that's
for sure his face has been all over the
pre-olympic publicity because he's a
defending champion but I think even
Matthew and would admit that the entry
here wasn't quite what he was looking
for ever so tiny over rotation of the
feet first Australian male to win
Olympic gold medal in diving since in
1924 when he got it - four years ago in
Beijing in the most spectacular fashion
with one of the great dives of all time
in the last round - snatch victory loves
competing you can see that with a smile
Almond his mervich of Norway
[Applause]
opening back two and a half somersault
with one and a half twists and he got
through everything here pretty tightly
feet just came together a little tardily
but he's gonna pick up some nice marks
here he's mervich with an eighty one
point six anything in the 80s is going
to leave you in good stead for your
second dive and onward german sanchez
huge first score of eighty nine point
one francesco de Lomo
from italy this is third olympic games
so an experienced competitor all the two
and a half somersault with one twist
piped very nice bring lots of experience
to be in ninth and the platform back in
Athens Oh for didn't make the final in
Beijing
not too much wrong in for Francesco just
a confidence-building start 72.5 will
need to build on that varying degrees of
pedigree in the countries diving history
really divers like Christopher s Gilson
from Sweden don't have a massive
tradition in this sport and facilities
sometimes more limited back two and a
half somersault one and a half twist for
his opening dive in keeps one of the
divers is really looking to get into
that semi-final first as a benchmark of
progress and achievement it's not a nice
job here try and get through the twists
as early as possible square yourself up
for the entry entry and not too much
wrong there from Christopher SQL some 23
years old trains in Malmo it just
bothered me a little it he wasn't quite
square but a seventy six point eight
that's all right he's top ten at the
moment
thirty-two in the field of course at
this stage
Eric sane from Canada his first Olympic
Games had success as a synchro diver but
he's on his own with a back two and a
half somersault two and a half twist
and again quite a high tariff dive to
open up your program with years and he
didn't quite get through it there was a
big splash because he wasn't vertical a
little bend at the hips on entry this
will show us so much more clearly in a
slow-mo all his knees were bent there
there were there were a number of
problems there and the judges have hit
him hard was messy I'm sorry I want to
be more complimentary maybe put the
tough one in early maybe to get it out
of the way but 59 4 is not too special
not in your first Olympic dive Brian
Nixon low-mass from Malaysia arm stand
back double somersault one and a half
twist to start his program his third
Olympic Games very nice
created a good entry even if he wasn't
completely vertical so he's ticked a
couple of boxes and maybe left one
uncheck but he's a former world junior
champion and he created history for
Malaysia when he achieved that in 2004
and he's got to get some good marks here
and with a reasonable tariff he'll be ok
with an 81 6 so that's good enough for a
equal fourth position at the moment next
up is Yvonne Garcia from Mexico on a
half of the silver medal winning duo in
the 10 meters synchro with German
Sanchez just 18
opening up with a forward
four-and-a-half somersault
spin speed going on there that's a three
point seven tariff as well not afraid to
put the tough dives in early he's got a
four point one coming later they did
roll over
it's a lot of somersaults to get through
in time to spot the water and get
yourself vertical and square so but 81.4
seventh the united states have had a bit
of their diving revival in these games
with such a huge early tradition in the
olympic games coming from the states
Nick McCrory has a bronze to take home
in the ten metre synchro with David
Boudia who's to dive in a few minutes
but he gets a chance to open his program
in with three and a half somersaults
well well my zeroes flash gets a warm
round of applause here from the crowd
that's will be reasonably neutral until
the British divers come up he can show
that bronze medal to his uncle the
British swimmer who in 1976 picked up
bronze in the 800 freestyle Gordon
Downey course Nick McCrory representing
the USA at a seventy six point eight
more than respectable announcer just
asking the enthusiastic crowd to turn
off the flash guns in their camera
phones and phones their cameras they
brought to record the events for now
there is quite enough light in here and
you don't distract me
the divers chose a carer from Cuba
getting on with his dive very sharply
indeed forward three and a half
somersault a little too quickly perhaps
there's the feet just slipped over at
the end of this one will be penalized
for that with six and a half sand sevens
a shame a lot only other parts of that
dive were nice but that last impression
is just vital it a bit and was we
compared with gymnastics that's like
sticking the landing after a tough
routine if you don't get the entry right
the judges have just left with a bad
impression
Sebastian via next from Colombia back
two and a half somersault one and a half
twist that's a three point two degree of
difficulty or very nice
a bronze medal in the Pan Am Games and
the 10-meter platform last year in
Guadalajara that's a sports festival
that's of gaining in prestige and is
attracting eights and that's a top-ten
dive at the moment still plenty to come
make start one of the big hitters as we
just see those marks confirmed there
David Boudia
from the United States bronze in the 10
metre synchro find foot 9 a much bigger
build diver of some of the 5 4 5 5 s
that we've seen already arm stands back
double somersault two and a half twists
three point six and opening the show
with a big number okay and be glad it's
got a big tariff because there were a
couple of small problems there done well
this was a dive that had the chance to
be up there in the top three but you
just observed that the biggest splash
there he likes the difficult dives he
chose the highest degree of difficulty
in the finals in 2008 in this event and
finished 10th so he likes to challenge
himself obviously first u.s. diver have
scores 600 plus points under the current
scoring system 8 now here's the star
possibly the the favorite Kubo from
China the world champion
in would three-and-a-half somersault to
put down his first marker his teammate
Lin is sitting in third position always
very tidy or the judges like it
and so frightening ly close to the
platform very vertical position slightly
bigger splash than perhaps he likes but
in 2/3 some of the big hitters have
ended up down the bottom end of this in
the in the draw for the dive order
they'll be seeded after tonight of
course this is Sasha Klein from Germany
twice European champion at 10 meters in
with three and a half somersault to
begin I've seen a few of these dives in
this first series and I'm too much
better than this one from Sasha Klein
very tidy very clean on entry 26 years
of age very experienced 8 golds and two
silvers at European Championship level
but this of course is very much a level
up but good opening 81.6 a popular score
in this first series and four other four
divers that on that score podium cap
tour from belarus another one of the
bigger eastern european divers at 5 foot
he did have a head injury last year and
in June when he hit the platform while
training with his apartment Tim I found
water check but this is a beautiful dive
take some courage to come back but
where's the splash he couldn't make one
and there's 72 the difficulty just down
a little that's why he's not our partner
in the high 70s the crowd as you can
hear already cheering because up on the
board is a great home hero Tom Daley
from Great Britain one of the poster
boys of the whole London 2012 Olympic
Games still only 18 years of age his
second Olympics so much expectation on
Tom Daley back two and a half somersault
two and a half twists and that's a three
point six to start with you know I would
like him to have done better so that the
crowd had a bit more to influence the
judges with but you saw the splash over
it came he's so clean through the air
but just let it go at the end and the
splash won't convince the judges that
this was a jet and a diver was in
control finished fourth in the 10 metre
synchro doing brilliantly in the first
three dives and then they've got the
fourth one wrong when it cost them
dearly cost him a medal he just has to
settle down and make sure he qualifies
and look to build through his through
his campaign he's not gonna win it
tonight but you can lose it it's not a
disastrous start but it's not a
confidence building one either she
oughta be mean from Italy in with three
and a half somersault
yep well some youth perhaps exposed with
his opening dovey his hips a little bent
on entry and the splash the world
sizable he got through somersaults well
enough but didn't straighten out quickly
enough it's still only 17 he was
outstanding in the European Youth
Championships in Budapest when he was
only 14 years of age and straightaway
was pitched in to the World
Championships in Rome in 2009 so he's
grown up in competition really second
last diver in this first series who go
Parisi from Brazil his third Olympic
Games forward three and a half
somersault made of a clean sound the
sound is almost an indication as much as
a sight you'll get good marks here but
with a 3.0 tariff you can't expect to
collect to bigger score nice entry down
from hugo top 15 one to come another big
cheer it's the other british diver Peter
Waterfield Tom Daley synchro partner
he's the older of the two by far age 31
and a local boy born in Walthamstow
which is just a few miles away in East
London we'll got plenty of experience
water-filled is well known really for
aquatic supporters
he's opening dive is an arm stand back
triple somersault three point three
tucked position very nice good start
it's his fourth Olympic Games so he
knows what this level of competition is
all about kick-out to start that
handstand I must hold that handstand to
show that the judges you were in control
biggest splash he's not a small man
powerfully-built not tall
165 centimeters but
very compact isn't he and a 66 repeater
room to improve and he'll need to in
this hot field and that completes the
first series of dives it's a long
scoreboard to give you but right at the
top there German Sanchez cleared
galperin and the two Chinese divers Lin
UA and Kubo both right up there Vaughn
da Sasha Klein some experienced divers
now maybe one or two who might have been
hoping for more like Matthew Mitchum and
David Boudia and Nick McCrory but this
these differences in points can be
caught up fairly quickly Tom Daly on the
line they're in 18th position he will be
believing he can only get better they'll
feel a lot better though from having got
into the competition got that first
nervous dive out of the way and start to
settle into their their routines as
we've said thirty two divers means it's
sort of a long evening when you're in a
final with just 12 then you're you're in
the water quickly and the whole
competition gets a lot more momentum
though the organization here is
excellent how swiftly they get them
standing at different levels of the
board and ready to go and keep the
entertainment going just under half an
hour for the first 32 dive so we can
expect half an hour per per dive per
series if you like
Alperin gets ready for exams down I
understand reverse triple age 27 born in
Moscow five foot nine terrible injury
problems we've had eight operations on
his back and knee and didn't compete in
2010 and 2011 it broke his leg as well
back in 2006 this is a dangerous sport
yeah and no wonder he thought about
their flagging it all away but his
family convinced him he should keep
going and he's had a very good second
dive here to confirm his position near
the top of the standings
- good dies from glib galperin
maybe these older more experienced
divers can bring that extra measure of
composure to their performance that's
the first dive man in the 90s Lin you
eight verse three and a half somersault
oh he's a little short on the entry
they're beautiful through the year as
always is that top Chinese divers see he
just didn't kick out early enough and
he's not vertical at all although
somehow he manages to make such a small
splash that's great control underneath
the water to pull that bubble down with
him like many of the divers here they
did take the chance to get a feel of the
pool by competing in a world cup event
which was held here at the Aquatic
Centre in February where he finished
sixth victor tiger somebody who really
likes to get on with it once he gets up
on that board he hears he'll help move
the competition along and his own way
forward three and a half
again really the only problem here that
the divers mostly have is ripping that
entry 67 and a half for Victor Anton
zakharov World Championships silver and
bronze in the synchro events 26 year old
with his second dive back three and a
half somersault very good control the
entry beautifully some strength earrings
Christie's team got a bit of ground to
make up really from his opening dive
very tight there chest and thighs
together
some of them grip all the way round the
back of their their legs they wanted to
them just like to hold it more to the
side but you can't really pull it in
can't you yes no good shot there under
the water the way they spread their arms
out that helps to pull the air down with
them the bubbles and then create a
better entry Timofey hold a cheek stand
back
triple somersault tucks three point
three the difficulty here which is as
high as his tariffs of dives go
Odia that was
that wasn't so special and the crowd
quite muted with their applause these
dives do give an impression without
actually analyzed them into elements all
the way down which the judges are doing
so the crowd the good crowd here very
quickly getting a feel for what's gonna
go down well by the size of the splash
although nothing there was the giveaway
for the crowd and the fours four and a
half sets that's tough for their chick
to come back from four more dives though
it can be done it's just you make it
hard for yourself put pressure on all
these divers have to qualify for this
competition either through the world
championships last year or being
Continental champion this is re here on
jus or having dived at the World Cup so
they will all earn the right to be here
very tidy through the year the second
jump off the platform is the toes lift
and then came on again and splash not
quite right the feet they've got to pull
out of that rotation and the speed they
generate then and that's where the the
core strength and those stomach muscles
really come into play where they've got
to basically put the brakes on in midair
mmm James Conner made a nervous start I
think it's fair to say with an opening
66 he was another one who was injured
back in 2010 and trained for a long time
with back pain 18 months it went on
eventually he had to give himself a rest
but he's back now back three and a half
somersault tucked
very nice a big improvement on his first
day particularly with the entry from
17-year old looks like he might have a
couple of risky issues as well after all
these divers learn to cope with injury
and compete with it if they can this is
really going to lift his school and saw
that the Tuck is quite split but does
allow them to go through the air a bit
more quickly seventy nine point two that
to picked up a few barks there tell by
his body language he feels a bit more
encouraged there Martin Wolfram from
Germany 20 year old
now 77.4 was his opening dive you're
starting to get a feel for what are the
kind of marks we can see helping the
divers progressed in the next round
dickish splash semi final will be
progress for him he competed at the
World Championships last year that was
his first really big international
competition finished 20th so he's
getting the top 18 here that would be a
good games for him and then you never
know young Claire
Aguilar of Cuba this is the the inward
three and a half we saw a lot of in the
first series
Oh beautiful agreed hey he only had a 61
and a half with his first dive and he
kept that in so tied to the platform and
just take your breath away watch here oh
but it allows him to get that more
vertical position he's not pushing out
too far away from the platform him
you're brave enough to keep it in that
close you can get more vertical and he
has taken some reward for his risk
it's a highly mouth moment there when
you look at those replays and it all
happened so quickly the replays really
give you the chance to appreciate the
sheer courage of these of these divers
they know what they're doing but even so
it's a 25 point improvement on with his
second dive agree Alexandre Banda now
from Ukraine flying himself into that
dive you do tend to get the Eastern
Europeans to really attack it in that
almost aggressive way he's jumping way
out into the pool here and that just
makes it a little tougher to get that
vertical position at a nice contrast
really to the previous diver with what
we're talking about getting into the
water at the right angle four and a half
somersaults he's got to generate there
he's got to get the the height and the
speed going has linked and then put
those brakes on 83 to five though with
that difficulty of three seven that
really helps Jihu Park from career in
with three and a half somersault he's
got work to do to try and make the cut
18 remember to go through
quick yeah and little under-rotated at
the finish to create that big splash but
again a little gasp from the crowd as
you see how tidy is to the board there I
think that he's here might have touched
the platform but fortunately not his
head they're all fine
kicks it out but over does it and that's
the giveaway splash 467 to make 10 mini
buyers also a three meter
diver as well sick from the 10 meter
synchro though already so he's got a
feel of the occasion very good this is
his toughest dive where 3.7 terror of
them he's got a couple of three sixes in
there as well fairly savage cut after
this after the preliminaries they almost
cut the field in half from 32 to 18
camera that slides down the pole and
gives you that look and some sense of
the pace
maybe six nine five so into the top five
for the moment but plenty of dives to
come in this second lot next up German
Sanchez the synchro silver medalist
likes this pool he was here in February
and got a silver there as well for the
two and a half somersault three twists
there was plenty of difficulty involved
with the three point eight tariff and
opened up of course with an 89 won he
helped me at the top of the standings to
the feet rolling over he's not going to
replicate that difficulty will help an
awful lot took control during that dive
and he just couldn't manage to quite
hold the right entry position there
maybe one seven still there about in
good shape to progress Riley McCormick
from Canada down in 19th place so he's
just below the cut needs to keep
improving back two and a half somersault
two and a half twists three point six
this one so he can make up ground here
[Applause]
few Canadians in the crowd perhaps
letting the judges know they approve a
little bit of loss of leg form at the
top of that dive the ankles should have
come together a bit quicker than that
and just a moderate sized splash here
his ankles are all over the place so he
didn't really capitalize on the
difficulty there 79 - though more than
respectable assistance
it could have been more coach being put
in his place Matthew Mitchum the
defending champion he feels that the
injuries he's had in recent years has
made him one of the underdogs here
tonight turned he is quite happy with
that back three and a half somersault
that should have improved his position
you think and three point three the
tariff I don't think we've seen this
dive yet from anyone else
and it's almost a blind kick out isn't
it you gotta try and reach that vertical
position with a little less to go by
it's the defending Olympic champion of
course so much expected of him and 74 to
his mervich didn't muck around Roger
right into it it's very noticeable have
someone to really compose themselves and
while we're watching the replays and
getting those results of course the
officials quickly get them moving up
there and ready to go and some of them
really are ready to go very nice entry
from gives mervich trains in sweden
there's no 10 metre platform facility in
Norway
[Music]
he's a bit of a trailblazer for Norway
they're in the diving
unlike francesco de Lomo italy have had
their stars in the past his second dive
forward three and a half somersault well
another impressive entry and just a
sense that the standard is now starting
to lift midway through this second
series that knows not quite on the knees
but the real impression is with the
entry and it was our beauty and so eight
eight now there's a couple of nines in
there as well they might get rejected
but they will in fact overall though did
he help the effort
seventy-six ninth lost the two nines of
course in the scoring system as you can
see them being crossed out there now
Christopher s Kilson from Sweden in with
three and a half a somersault 13th in
round one so it'll be reasonably
encouraged by his opening dive
right entry
a second look here very tight tuck
position spots the water not quite 100%
vertical but so you need a second look
to see that it's all about the entry
he's competed at the last two World
Championships and never gone out of the
qualifying stage so he's giving himself
a bit of a chance here perhaps seventy
six eight he's in equal seventh position
moving up from 13th
now Eric Sain did not get off to a great
start
he was right down the bottom of the
pecking order in 30th inward three and a
half somersaults and he needs to get
this a lot more impressively
well maybe it was better but it needed
to be better than that
if I can put it as simply as that these
divers he was taken along to the pool by
mum or dad and they have a swim gym
program in Canada that he turned up at
one day and thought he rather liked it
and his diving career took off as Steve
said a lot of these divers progressed
from gymnastics or trampolining one or
two have had injuries and think rather
mistakenly this might be a slightly
can't be a softer option can it's a
different option we'll say 62 for
therefore Eric same move on to us
forward four and a half somersault tucks
there 3.7 the tariff he's named in part
after one of your great footballers
there Bryan Robson
so he's dead must be a huge football fan
Nick in Malaysia Bryan Robson wouldn't
have held back I can tell you that he'd
have been diving he really would have
given it the full face of the bat and
the trouble for this Brian was that he
wasn't it didn't quite straighten out
the legs below the hips here and he's
come in a bit of an angle
Malaysia never won an Olympic gold medal
before these games so it'd be a great
incentive but might still be in the
dreams perhaps he's second I'll just
letting him down a little as we move
swiftly on even Garcia up in ninth place
right on the edge of that board back
three and a half somersault that in
itself a real test of nerve for most
people
all very good but they do have to take
their time in that position and make
sure they've got the composure right on
the edge of the board they're no spring
to be had out of concrete so they really
need the power out of the legs and he
has controlled that entry beautifully
fancier and he's getting it a sprinkling
of nines for this dive which will really
move him up the standings third it's a
great camera angle that Top Shot looking
right down and really gives you an idea
of the view from the top there which is
formidable
Nick McCrory from the United States
armed stands back double somersault one
and a half twist
he's 13th equal this in itself for a
test getting right to the edge of that
board basically three stories up in the
air
agonizing wench at the top was was I
just thought is he in control here as he
got all his thoughts together but the
execution was fine he did kick out a
little horizontally and I was wondering
if he was going to get through all that
he had to but he reached a beautiful
position for the entry and it was well
in control the nerve at the top of that
board - just hold on hold on until you
know you're absolutely right we know how
much they practice but even so in this
atmosphere with this pressure and
expectation you really have got to
admire their skill in their sheer nerve
putting a towel down quite a few of them
there just to get that a little bit of
extra grip and feel Jose Guerra of Cuba
back three and a half somersault had a
poor first dive needs this to be good oh
it's not our dear well your heart goes
out wasn't it yeah and he's head drops
he knows all too well that this went
seriously wrong picked out too early and
he's almost hit horizontally I did
complete the dive if you do complete the
dive he will get a a score like if you
just sort of opted out half through then
it will be deemed to be incomplete and
that is a zero but to be fair the crowd
were really supportive there I thought
and sympathetic Sebastian Villar now
from Colombia the crowd realized that
what these men are doing they could
never do so there's that respect in with
three and a half somersault piked
man you could start with a 78 for and
I'll get full value here with some
problems on the entry like he's formed
through the air wonderful position their
spots the water then twists and must be
square on as well as vertical
he wasn't quite either 71-75 then
next up the synchro bronze medalist from
last week David Boudia who does confess
that he's been to see sports
psychologists because doesn't have a
great deal of confidence with Heights
which is a bit unfortunate when you're
standing on the edge of a 10 meter board
but he's got an in with three and a half
somersault now I think he's got the
problem sorted but I'd I'd need the same
I think he attacked that voted me one of
the number of divers to score in the 80s
with his first
not quite
so prodigious with his second hands a
flat as the end of the water they're not
pointed and that helps create a hole -
for the body to follow into the water
with 73 6-4 the diet
next up the favorite chuubo 25 perfect
tens when he got a historic 609 20 the
diving World Series in Beijing last year
like triple somersault my goodness what
an entry how does he do it he does it
with a bow and there was no splash it
could have been a pea entering the water
and the judges loved it was a 10 in
there look at that entry position well a
couple of those 10th well at the two
tens unfortunately for him could cast
aside but it is a very high score to
boat what an impression to leave 99.75
they really are poker faced throughout
their program the Chinese divers they
really don't like to let their emotions
come through so controlled all the way
through the evening and it's a long
evening for them Sasha Klein now from
Germany forward four and a half
somersault
well he got away with a good entry there
having not really established a vertical
position you might feel he's in that
group outside the big guns challenging
perhaps for medal honors the next 24
hours
passes don't even some ourselves to get
through good entry just hips slightly
bent there but 88.8 done you're not
gonna argue with that kind of mark Klein
into fourth position at the moment early
in the prelims Bodine capped or now from
Belarus with work to do in with three
and a half somersault with which to make
some progress three-point to the tariff
when if TN one of these inward dives
that has the crowd a little concerned
about how close he was to the platform
us to judge it to yourself here makes a
beautiful entry though
[Applause]
while we wait for those very solid marks
indeed the crown are already getting
excited because it's Great Britain's Tom
Daley on the board next and he and
Jessica Ellis were the two pre-games
faces that you saw absolutely everywhere
in the country Jessica's got her gold
which doubles the pressure on Tom in
with three and a half somersault tucked
not really settled yet
that's better
only a 73 eight for his first dive it
can't let the field get away from him
here almost a third of the way through
the competition need something in the
high 70s if he can muster it and he's
been a star ever since he was 14 years
of age in Beijing the youngest
competitor in the team outside of
swimming Britain's second youngest ever
olympian world champion of course in
Rome in 2009 at 15 and it's been one
long marathon of expectation but he's
getting there
and the high 70s is what he has achieved
so improvement will help aundrea
Cherubini from italy arm stand back
triple somersault for the 17 year old
from Rome
what I didn't want to hold it too long
he was ready well that's an entry that
true bow would be plead pleased with it
barely a ripple pulled it in nicely
judges not too impressed I just wonder
whether he wasn't in that controlled
handstand position for long enough for
the judges to be happy
bit too anxious to get on with it
basically must give the impression of
control and time they have to have
control it's just not going to happen
otherwise we'll go Parisi from Brazil
gives you a sense of how far up it is
doesn't at that low angle in with three
and a half somersaulting never got
beyond the preliminary round in two
Olympic Games before a little bit heavy
perhaps
and the one diver left in this second
series and is an Englishman big splash
there doesn't help but you go Parisi
scores spots the ward up it's not quite
there
again the crowd are willing on the final
diver of 32 Peter Waterfield from Great
Britain who's had his injury problems
with a virus before the last World
Championships he's had shoulder injuries
a neck injury more recently but the 31
year old is still here and competing and
ready to do an inward three and a half
somersault well the crowd reaction told
you most things about the entry well he
only had a 66 with his first time and
needed improvement not a problem and the
problem is what his head here as the
legs go way over he's just got through
it too quickly it's over rotated
but a silver in Athens in 2004 with Leon
Taylor and the 10-meter synchronized I
was nearly at the bottom of the field
with that second dive unfortunately for
water-filled at 31st so there is a big
mountain to climb
Kubo ascending to his a customary
position there at the league lib
galperin german sanchez sasha klein even
Navarro the Mexicans continuing to do
well David Boudia has pulled up a little
bit as well Tom Daley up to 15th he
might have to come out of the pack as it
were to try to get into a good position
rather like running a 10k out there on
the track not too far away where you get
through those qualifying rounds in shape
and look to build that's certainly what
the crowd in this fantastic 17,000
seater Aquatic Centre will be hoping
down there on that caption these are the
ones who are really are just wanting to
be back here in the morning and to make
their olympic games more than a six dive
wonder Peter Waterfield there the other
home favorite with a huge amount of work
to do Matthew Mitchum also on the bubble
sitting in the 16th position so he can't
afford to have things go wrong but
clipped galperin
it's made a very good start - excellent
dives that would probably be the worst
of his three galperin was first after
the first rotation second after the
second forward three and a half
somersault there for the Olympic Games
bronze medalist in Beijing
you'd make the syncro team just a 66 for
his third drive that's disappointing one
for alprin interestingly enough neither
of China's gold medal-winning 10 metre
synchro team actually made the
individual competition which is just
astonishing
lynnie way oh goodness me back there and
a half somersault there and he's
starting to show his pedigree I think
and now we're seeing why they come to
this event as favourites
what a position he adopts what an entry
he achieves and what splash slicing into
the water there look how tight he is
there really hugging those legs enormous
flexibility don't just slim look at the
power and the muscle definition on his
thighs and the push-up and the the
stomach muscle strength to pull out of
those dives there's a 100 point dive
Victor Ortega from Colombia previously
competed at the Olympics in the synchro
event arm stand back triple somersault
tucked
you know respectable 25th after the
second dive so he's fighting to be back
tomorrow morning
nice didn't really control the entry
it's got three more dives consolidate
his position
Anton zakharov just missed out in a
synchro medal back in 2004 at the
Olympic Games
while those high-speed forward four and
a half somersaults tucked with a 3.7
tariff if you nail it well it always
looked like he did have it in control
not to horizontal with his takeoff from
the platform their ankles just slightly
apart made a good job of the entry some
from column a some from column B as we
separate he's got his little support
crew here certainly tell the Ukrainians
and have very distinctive KITT they wear
spot them a mile off with anything in
the eighties you'll take and he's had 72
and 88 and on 83
Timofey weld a chick he was right down
in 30th position forward three and a
half somersaults was the intention there
he's come up short hasn't he never got
through it just struggling to reach he's
best in this competition and might be
struggling to explain why
see his head well away from the knees
compared to our two Chinese stars just a
different position he can still make
that work
but he didn't on that occasion she own
Jewry we're on that ten meter board from
the Democratic People's Republic of
Korea just sixteen years of age on stand
back triple somersault now how quickly
will he be into the dive from his whole
position up very quickly always not got
it there or we can do it again but there
is a there's a time on this and more
than anything else this is a major test
good luck well he had to hurry that to
get into the position again and a
reminder of just how big that part of
the dive is a test and not just to be
taken for granted what they're doing
before they even set off so he had to
rush it in the end and under some
pressure he's flopped over over-rotated
big splash will be a difficult dive to
come back from
the feeling of panic when he lose that
then when it is all about composure at
the top of that board must be absolutely
unimaginable so he's really been
punished there the score of 18 that is
that's crippling that is that's a waffle
Jimmy Connor 17-year old Australian in
with three and a half somersaults back
in 24th needs to put on a bit of a show
here if he's going to be back in the
morning
well he could be having a late night
tonight not at 17
taking a long time to get said well I
was concerned for him because he seemed
to be there an age convincing himself
when to go
and yet he's done a good job here it
must be almost like getting the yips you
know had golfers and even they call it
dart itis in darts when you can't let go
he's got it right in the end
well played there's some concession to
his youth you one of the younger divers
at 17 at a seventy six point eight so
one in the mid-60s and two in the high
70s he's hanging around there
Martin Wolfram from Germany he was here
in February in the World Cup finished
ninth at this height reversed three and
a half somersault oh good job and he was
19th after the second dive so me too is
right on that cut and just needed to be
as good as it turned out to be this is a
wonderful entry Martin Wolfram and has
really surged up the standings with this
one
not sure how much of that lack of a
square position the judges will see they
haven't punished him forward really with
an 87 45 some nines in the Earth's
that's a great effort yang Claire Aquila
from Cuba back three and a half
somersault
he's down 20 second position so it's
within range the difficulty here is
three point six for the back three and a
half somersault well didn't quite get
there and this was his highest tariff
dive or he's got another one coming for
his last that's also three point six
these are the ones you really need to
make most use of he got to the
semi-final in last year's World
Championship so he would have probably
come to London expecting at least to
come back for a second round of dives
but this is the world's best it's going
to be difficult big splash on injury
there four and a sixty four point eight
that won't help him
Ukrainian Alexander Banda 18 year old
from Lugansk with a stand back double
somersault two and a half twists and
he's up in sixth place needs to just get
that arm stand straight he's there
it's to live
no it has to take something out of the
shoulders being in that position that
long seem to be almost too keen to get
into the twist before he'd really got
himself away from the board
yeah and he was bent at the hips bad
position entering the water the ankles
came apart also so there was some leg
form issues throughout the dive only
came together at the end but the the
entry was not too special so a fifty
seventy six and vonda is gonna plummet
down the rankings when all said and done
after the third consistency that's the
the big test across six dives
Jihu Park from Korea twenty-year-old
back three and a half somersault
and has ever done that one as well he
he's struggling really Park not his
night must be so hard to put the
previous dive behind you and and start
from scratch every time it's a bit like
a bit like a golfer stepping up on the
tee again after a double bogey and
needing to clear all the negatives out
and starting again with each dive he
just never got into a really tight tuck
position even the split tuck would have
helped him get through those rotations
more quickly so some technique issues
there for Park
Victoire mini bive synchro partner of
idiot Zack it off
reverse three and a half somersault
another long wait at the top there
well very nice 11th after two dives I
don't think he's gonna give up any
ground with that one you know half an
arm movement at the top there we looked
as though he wasn't quite sure and then
he was all very positive judges are
fairly happy with it the the feet just
rolled over at the very end but very
positive entry after a rough start a 67
with his first dive 86 9 5 his second
and then 82.5 for his third so starting
to produce it
next up it's 20 year old German Sanchez
from Guadalajara in Mexico who's having
an excellent games silver medal from the
synchro already in his kit and third
after two dives and now with an arm
stand back triple somersault how long
will it take him to get into that key
position legs wide in closing
well he looked more confident that at
the top than he did at the bottom where
the entry was less than ideal he's got a
little bit of room to play with having
come into this series well-positioned
former Cunha world silver medalist at 10
meters that was only in 2010 so they are
so young these competitors many of them
follows a professional footballer so you
should know a little bit about diving
there's one or two footballers a little
bit that's unkind but it's well worked
in there nice segue
seventy seventy five point nine for his
third as we move under Riley McCormick
from Canada kings in with
three-and-a-half somersault lovely at
McCormick they'll be proud of that one I
think especially the entry this is a
zero splash dive if you like just pulls
that water down with him the air that
he's created the arms separate it's a
bit of a technique to this to ripping
the entry and give him nine out of ten
for the entry not that they separate
them but you know sitting up here
weekend and an 80 from Arizona State
University combining his diving with his
studies in the United States he wants
our job career in broadcasting Matthew
Mitchum I think he needs to make a
statement now amateur manie's he's just
had a pedestrian couple of first two
dives him with three and a half
somersault for the defending champion
that's better well the evidence shows
that he knows how to pull out the big
one on the big occasion but he has left
himself a little bit more work than he
would have expected very good entry and
he's going to pull some eights and a
very split tuck position but then pulls
it back together again for the entry
competed in the 3-meter springboard at
the last Olympics didn't qualify for the
final but now concentrating and it's got
a mark in the 80s - let's move him up
the rankings we'll see when everyone's
finished three armand gives Mavic from
norway back three and a half somersault
he's 12
competed it to one meter and the world
championships one meter of course not an
Olympic event his problem there was that
even in the tuck position his feet
weren't aligned and the judges Sidon
would have been able to see that as
perhaps you did too that's an unusual
error really
in the 6435 for his mervich looks to be
good camaraderie around the pool we love
seeing that at the Olympics even at the
very top level at the athletes my
friends we've seen plenty of that in all
the sports across the games which has
been great Francesco del mo because it's
a long Lee a lonely place rather at the
top of that board in with three and a
half somersault very good Francesco come
up smiling he sometimes get a sense of
how the diver feels about and how
quickly they come to the surface well
here's some of this applause I thought
that went alright what's the crowd thing
well they liked it he was a European
silver medalist back in 2004 so he's had
a good length career to know how to deal
with these occasions eighty one six
Christopher s Kilson from Sweden who's
doing too badly 12th equal after three
dives and now an arm stand back triple
somersault
while he executed the dive okay but he
didn't look convincing in the handstand
he once he reached a position where he
felt confident he did move but he hadn't
held it for long
judges aren't too unhappy with him he
was pretty vertical for the entry even
if it wasn't a low splash affair
and a seventy two point six
these boys that are sort of on the
bubble that brings its own pressure when
you get about halfway through the
competition you realize that you can't
muck up a dive
Eric Sain said it was a dream come true
just to be at the Olympics and admitted
that he'd said his stall out to get to
the final was his ambition but he's got
some work to do I'm staying back double
somersault two and a half twist he's
back in 29th oh dear that was short he
almost fell off the platform he's had a
couple of poor dives only three
competitors below him and this wonder
what's going on here for Eric he's a
better driver than this well you'll look
at that as I'm sure he will and realize
that he can do better
Canadian champion at the individual and
the synchro events picked up medals
pan-american games Commonwealth Games
but this is a big step up in the Olympic
Games and 55.8 for Eric he's going to be
disheartened by that Brian Lomas from
Malaysia trains in China with facilities
you won't be surprised to discover our
top quality back three and a half
somersault
oh well that's seriously overcooking it
a fairly straightforward dive it's a
shame for him the crowd reaction told
you everything there let alone what the
judges would make of it just tumbling
into it like a chimney being demolished
yeah that's a 29.7 such a low score that
it could be hard to recover from with
three dives to come and he too is better
than that if you look at his past record
now the Mexicans are on a bit of a
charge in this diving competition even
Garcia v the synchro silver medallist
Pan American double champion seventh of
the world's last year this is
competition that he's familiar with
standard he can match still only 18 so
he is obviously progressing in his
career the inward four and a half
somersault tucked four point one the
tariff here a big one
well okay when you've got that big
tariff you really are looking to play
your Joker as they say and get the
almost the double points let's look for
the problems he had by the time he
reached the water here that the legs
weren't where he wanted them to be they
were they weren't straight from the hips
and they weren't together at the ankles
and the judges will get him for that
just a slight twist
seventy seven point nine now and the the
difficulty certainly helps boost the
score on to Nick McCrory from Durham
North Carolina studying maths at Duke
University so he'll be able to work out
his own scores quick and the judges
perhaps or do have a little bit of
computer aid be quick forward four and a
half somersault worth three point seven
different ways to take the photo these
days they hit the tablet out and just
watch the entry here he made a good job
with the zero almost zero splash but
flies to a vertical position that
certainly helped but I think the judges
would see that he hadn't achieved a
vertical position
Koza Guerra from Cuba bringing up the
rear at the moment it's worth pausing to
look at that great score that linear
he's now fifteen points clear of the
field we haven't finished this third
series but hundred points will help you
every time all very nice
Oh Jose Guerra oh please the Cubans
we've got a silver at the World
Championships at 10 meters back in 2005
so suddenly finding rats Allah form well
he was nowhere uh after the second
series he had a disastrous second dive
he's put that well out of his mind to
produce a stellar effort maybe a bit of
encouragement there not just for Jose
but also for every other diver who's
starting to think that he might have
missed the boat that was brilliant as a
city it's his fourth Olympic Games he
has got diving pedigree that's live and
they crown up as well
Sebastian via now he's seventeenth
cannot afford to drop his standards with
an arm stand back triple somersault all
but he has and that's well short of the
vertical scanning back through Guerra's
dives at 3:58 2192 a model of
inconsistency proves he's a fighter
well that's a shame just an ADA it's the
best in be agony for the coaches and the
family and everybody else here
supporting fair old tricks from Colombia
David Boudia
tense so far not as far as it is from
Australia Roger
very true very true very nice it was
like a second splash if you will he
didn't quite control the air under the
water there it was a funny one those
four and a half somersaults tucked there
was a lot of tumbling momentum to try
and bring under control at the end for
the entry they're pulling him forward
it's the best American platform diver
among the men since the great Greg
Louganis one of the iconic names from
diving in the past when America
absolutely dominated at this event
before China decided to enter and
spoiled their party a little bit well he
inspired many to take up the sport
didn't he's such a master of it
springboard and platform and that famous
crack on the board which we do not want
to see repeated to bow now the star oh
and again he sets a very high standard
nice and tidy into the platform
the crowd is being treated here there's
some world-class diving particularly
from the two Chinese just 19 years of
age he's the son of a factory worker
from C chuan uncle was a gymnast and the
big marks are coming out for the big
dives now throw out the two nines and
the ten and you just left with nine and
a half's butcher boat and a 90 405 and
now he leads linear China one two no
shock there Sascha Klein though wanting
to make the statement in this
preliminary round that he is a genuine
medal contender we'll worry about the
color of that medal afterwards an arm
stand back triple somersault were three
point five for the German diver
excellent job good effort with that one
Sascha Klein he's not gonna give up too
much ground without I would he wouldn't
think having come into his third dive in
fourth position he's a soldier serves in
the army who obviously are very
accommodating and give him plenty of
training time I would imagine looks
happy with it and a 9275 why wouldn't
you be Maxie's best dive sofa 81 88 and
92 I think you might be on the bookies
blackboard that one I think that special
client could be somebody who is in
contention
although the way the Chinese are
starting to emerge that will have just
to be all competing for third place I'd
even capped off now I'd look to be
struggling in his departure from the
platform but he knew what he was doing
got through it forward double somersault
with a twist after that arm stand
not even allowed to enjoy his dive again
and wait for the scores because you know
who is on next it's got two mates in
there though but him kept or or a score
of 74 for and 16th this needs to keep
impressing Tom Daly who was given the
honor of making the first dive in this
pool when it was officially opened July
last year with exactly one day one year
to go to the day to the opening of the
games arm stand back triple somersault
he's back in 15th remaining you 18 to
move on to the semi so it's gonna keep
some good dives coming
he's recovered that well he had a moment
of unsteadiness in the handstand
collected himself and executed well
crowds absolutely loved him he's had
problems as a youngster
obviously the terribly sad story of his
father dying he was such a an influence
obviously in a massive active supporter
he was bullied at school for a while and
such a nice chap as well he's such a
nice dive in there and I think an eighty
nine to five and Tom Daly starting to
find the confidence needed to just move
on to the next part of the competition
doing a bit of a gesture nice they're
just withdrawing into himself and
keeping that composure in between dives
and they pull a long wait I'm doing a
tiara beany back three and a half
somersault he's way down in 28th he
still might be down there too after over
rotating there and making a bit of a
mess at the entry at 17 these teenage
divers have a lot of chance to come
again and continue to progress I think
you have to taste this level of
competition and the pressure that comes
with it to deal with it and then make
the most of it next time it's it's a
rear Olympian who steps up the first
time and nails it especially at that age
you're used to seeing that with the
gymnastics where also they start
fronting Lee Jung know they do but not
as young as they used to they've made a
few restrictions to age and the women
have to be turning 16 the year of the
Olympic competition Parisi from Brazil
he's not having the best of days either
that back three and a half somersault
and he by contrast
Hugo is 28 he just never quite got there
when he had quite an angle and made
quite a splash but not in a good way
they've done that dive so many times but
it's all about delivering it on the day
Peter Waterfield from Great Britain who
it's having a very disappointing evening
so far but the terrific crowd here
predictably right behind him forward
four and a half somersault well this is
his big dive it's the three point seven
difficulty and he's about to make up but
a serious amount of ground here the
crowd doing their best to influence the
judges he was competing back in 1997 a
world championship level so he does know
how to put these things behind him well
that was a wonderful dive that's a view
as he goes past the judges has got to
get those feet together they can't
afford to blink the judges Ken you know
it's there's actually two panels worked
through this long session to make sure
that the job's done with fresh eyes
ninety four three five that's well done
him
that'll help he looks as though he's
pleased with that quite rightly so
showing his fighting qualities let's
check on that leaderboard then halfway
through the competition
Qubo leading from the front but Sasha
climbed from Germany up there in second
place Lynn you a German Sanchez galperin
the second Mexican even Garcia Tom Daley
progressing up to ninth and just after
hear the next caption will give you
where the cut is these are the people
who are really under the pressure at the
moment it's not those at the top it cap
to a bondage
Connor Victor Ortega there all around
that cattle 18 that is their objective
and it is tight around there
half a dozen points will make all the
difference
see Peter Waterfield made up some ground
with that third dive but still 17 away
from that little group on the bubble so
he has got to have a couple more good
dives but it can be done I only made
three or four ahead of you to stumble
again they're keeping very well tightly
to schedule here the one of the features
when you go from event to event not just
in the diving Paul is the the
competition organization how quickly
they get every sport ready and the whole
thing is like clockwork really to a very
strict time schedule so back to the top
of the order we go lib galperin from
russia double world champion and Olympic
bronze medalist lovely dive to start the
fourth and he's never been out of the
top five in the competition this evening
and I think he might just stay there
that was well-executed confidently done
this man as we've discussed is come back
from a series of terrible injuries and a
host of operations and still performing
at the top comes from a sporting family
his father works in diving for the
Russian Ministry of sport and his mother
there's a master of sport in gymnastics
so he's got it from both sides there
plenty of guidance a couple in the 80s
and 91 and they're just that their dive
of 66 for Easter but let's enjoy linear
four and a half somersault
speed of that well he can certainly
somersault he didn't quite pull it up in
quite the right way as flipped over the
feet here at that split tuck position to
get through the splash means that he
won't be getting nines actually broke
the 600 barrier four points in the 2010
national championships in China 603
point four five an astonishing total and
he's rattling up they are a 92 they're
there they're just so consistent used to
average 100 per dive rageous yeah Victor
Ortega from Colombia xx you was in with
a shout inward three and a half
somersault that needs to make progress
it's planning to be a lawyer when he
finishes competing and give something
back to the sport she's lovely to hear
hope he's not done yet
interesting the height there off the
board he got trying to get through those
somersaults almost before they go back
down at a lovely position just a
slightly larger splash and a 73 6-4
tiger
went on zakharov had more success at
synchro competition than when in the
individual dives reverse four-and-a-half
somersault it's just a little arched on
entry there Raji's won't get the full
value for it it's looking very solid to
be back again tomorrow morning though
unless he has a disaster later on fairly
tight into the platform it's really
reaching to try and pull that entry he's
been competing at a world championship
level since 2001 he's only 26 which
gives you an idea for the 16 and 17 year
olds that we're seeing just how their
career can develop over the long term
and they could be back for 2-3 Olympics
Timofey audio check of Belarus in with
three and a half somersault thirty first
personal pride perhaps his main
motivation here
that's a better one he's had a couple of
indifferent dives for the air chick
pride might indeed have motivated him
here he's just managed to put the poor
dives to one side come up with a better
one if not quite the splash he would
have liked that divers don't see the
splash but I'm sure they get a sense of
it and a sixty eight eight for him
now hyungjoo Democratic People's
Republic of Korea he's a 16 year old the
back three-and-a-half somersault this is
a competition for real experience one
suspects from Pyongyang he's just
finding that I can't bring his best
dives to this I wonder if we will have
see better from him when another Olympic
cycle rolls past but that's a very poor
entry at this level only five foot one
he must be one of the smallest divers in
the competition but rather deflating
marks there now Jimmy Conner the 17 year
old he's just at 19 I'm standing back
double somersault one and a half twists
from Melbourne but he lives in Brisbane
trains there splits the family up her
dad lives in Melbourne mum lives with
him sacrifices that families make all
sorts of ways to get to the handstand
and this is James he's there it's the
important thing
and he just over-rotated on the entry
there it's a big strain on a young lad
not just competing here but as we
mentioned there you know when the family
has to split up to back him and the it's
what city the whole family invests in
that sporting future is a nice errific
pressure on a young lad
yes brisbane some sixteen hundred
kilometres from melbourne it's it's no
overnight trip i can tell you to get the
family back together a sixty-four
therefore james martin wolfram from
dresden in germany tenth back
three-and-a-half somersault having a
pretty good evening so far nearly
and see what went wrong here was made me
again
the most obvious error and in quite a
nice position here nose to the knees
didn't straighten it out in time for an
impressive entry
you'd be fairly pleased so far though
he's sitting comfortably in the frame
and just has to keep it steady and get
on with his work really yeah three point
six difficulty helped him out there to
achieve an 84 six should be alright
young Claire I get up from Cuba started
diving when he's just six years of age
I'm staying back double somersault one
and a half twist back downing twenty
seconds so he needs to point out a solid
score here to keep in touch
certainly got through the twist nice and
early but a little bit of an angle on
the entry just a touch short see how the
hands have got to move they tend to put
one behind there the back of the head
and one down the side and they're
straight away then changing hand
position as they as they dive unravels
they're 70 point four four angry they're
awful lot to think about him what
amounts to about one point eight seconds
the dive takes a lot of moving parts to
get aligned at the last moment for the
entry bond or from Ukraine
eighteen-year-old back three and a half
somersault there and they say teeth he
has just nailed one there aleksander
bond or he's he's gonna be happy with it
school here surely because he has ripped
a wonderful entry and the nines are
coming for bond or that should really
have taken him away from that position
right on the edge of the cut at eighteen
that's just a bit too uncomfortable
going into the closing rounds don't
think of Ukraine as a place where they
play billiards but he does good hobby
away from diving everyone needs a
distraction from their main focus they
find other things to do get crazy with
only one focus
Chiho Park from Korea twenty-fourth
reverse two-and-a-half somersault just
2.9 the tariff here it's not going to
get him a huge amount of marks will
you've got a low tariff dive you've got
to get as much technical standard as
possible together decent score
competitors from north and south of the
border in Korea just finding this level
of competition beyond them it would seem
in these preliminaries
so Parker 37 7 so I don't think we will
see him in action in the morning Victor
mini PI F arm stand back double
somersault two and a half twists in 11th
position 3.6 the degree of difficulty
here European silver medalist in his
first Olympic Games
getting that long hold at the top it was
an impressive rise to handstand
initially held it for quite a long time
and didn't execute the back end of the
dive through the twist spots the water
and I think that really the entry is the
only thing he's going to get penalized
for because the rest of the dive looked
very tired a nice leg form good position
and just can't keep the splashdown 77
for Alvin Mexicans again who have a
strong diving tradition having a more
than respectable Games to silver and a
bronze so far in these games and German
Sanchez is fourth so far in this proven
Eric competition to have tough dive this
one Roger in with four a half somersault
how close to the board he gets
but to push out and then dive having you
and get through those somersaults so
quickly you just gotta rip them around
to have any chance to get there's no
running jump at these four and a half
somersaults so that's why it attracts
the four point one he's through at least
two before he comes back down level with
that ten meter board and a ninety eight
point four without big difficulty
working off those scores of eight he's
comfortably back tomorrow and with force
overnight perhaps of just how much
potential he can bring to bear come the
end of the day Riley McCormack getting
up into an arm stand back triple
somersault for three point three ranked
13 the Canadian he's just over-rotated a
little on the entry who is up to the
handstand the arm stand very confidently
competed in Beijing when he was just 16
finished 16th that's 10 meters he will
be looking to build on that back for
years later at 69 3 the McCormick is
allow us to his for dive so far so
ranging from that up to 80 now what are
we gonna get from Matthew Mitchum the
defending champion Eminem they call him
well he's a bit like a box of chocolates
you're not sure what you're gonna get
he's been a little bit inconsistent at
least in this competition reversed three
and a half somersault with a three point
three Terrace
well the splash will tell you a bit and
he doesn't want to pop his head up too
early he won't be too thrilled with the
execution here he started as a
trampoline list as well competing at
World Junior Championship level and
nearly got to an Olympics in
trampolining which has become quite a
popular sport in Australia
he's certainly putting some pressure on
himself to make tomorrow morning it's
got to be more there there's obviously a
lot more there can he dig it out though
you know returning Olympic champions has
found it so hard to replicate all the
distractions that happen in the
intervening years Armond gives me Vic
from Norway the 21 year old a traverse
two and a half somersault only had a two
point sound seven tariffs so it demands
a high level of execution and he didn't
have it Roger there's a major splash at
the end of this kicked it out quite
elegantly but then the toes weren't
pointed the angle wasn't right and he's
being marked down
it was very good until it wasn't very
few Norwegians making it to this level
of competition francesco de Lomo from
italy 15 back three and a half
somersault can't afford to get anything
radically wrong just needs to keep it
solid to make sure he's back tomorrow
yeah what a bit of water there and he
was up so quickly didn't really manage
to pull the dive down into the water and
minimize the splash he he's got two
dives of this difficulty three point
three and he's coming at such an angle
he's popped up straight away and not
made the most of this
just couldn't pull the air in after him
and a41 2:5 for francesco that will not
help because he's in that area between
sort of 15 and 20 top 18 to progress
remember Christopher s Gilson from
Sweden
23 year old back three and a half
somersault he's 16th just making the cut
at the moment three point three the
tariff here oh yeah
and the crowd gasps and we'll just leave
that one to the judges because you saw
as well as we did he would have seen
that a diver before him duomo in a
similar position in terms of rankings
make a mistake and he had a chance to
capitalize just made him move up that
one more spot but if anything he's put
in a worst dive 39 6s Gilson so tough
for pressure but you that's what the
sport is you just have to deliver it on
the day I won't go a goal down and pull
it back in the second half it's just not
that sort of an event
Eric st. from Canada that's better
he's had a fairly wretched night until
now forward three and a half somersault
there with a 3.0 degree of difficulty
well this was the dive he could manage
he's control and really a little bit
bent in that Pike position it has to be
acknowledged
entry a lot better some very successful
synchro divers do find it a different
proposition where they can up there on
their own and it's all about the
execution and there's no backup scores
for the synchronization which counts
very heavily in the team event as they
call it now our friend Brian Lomas from
Malaysia
reverse three-and-a-half somersault
that's better he's had a slightly
erratic evening himself and some of the
Malaysian support for him I'm sure he's
a bit of a legend back home the nation
doesn't turn out an enormous number of
athletes on the world stage
insert Olympic Games carried the flag
for Malaysia in the opening ceremony
back in 2004
well I believe he was the youngest
smallest and lightest at participant I'm
sure he managed the flag okay and a
seventy four to five back up now towards
the top of the rankings with the Mexican
even Garcia armed stand back double
somersault two and a half twists three
point six the multiplier here and he's
in a decent position six after round
three and you sense real confidence in
the Mexican camp legs spread wide before
close together to get that hold position
just right
yeah well reasonably tidy
three-point-six the degree of difficulty
so it will be boosted by that but there
were just a question mark about whether
he got through all the twists in time to
straighten up and achieve that vertical
position and he was a little hinged at
the hips is it giving the camera away
with a taupe that is an angle isn't it
we've got them all covered here 81
arriving 91 different recognized
platform dives you can pick from
everyone a a challenge some greater than
others to say the least
Nick McCrory's up next from the United
States a synchro bronze medalist
reversed three and a half somersault
well ranked 12th coming into this dive
number four and I don't think you'll be
giving up ground there there was a very
decent effort a little bit of a splash
on entry but reaching for the sky
tucking in tight getting through them as
well reaching for the water pretty good
position but the smaller splash you'll
see but a very solid job done with his
dive
I'm sure he will have set himself the
target of reaching the final tomorrow
evening he's finished six for the world
championships last year 70 9.2 his
chances not damaged by that anything
around the 80 keeps you just bubbling
along and heading for more competition
quasi Guerra his fourth dives an arm
stand reverse triple somersault he's
back down in 30th position
Huber's greatest ever diver and he's the
oldest diver in the competition oh well
let's ease three-point-four tariffs he
just be about to make a bit of a
statement here at 33 years of age
she's fourth Olympics competed in five
World Championships so he knows what
it's all about and suddenly pulling out
that level I wonder he's really not it's
got a little bit of competition to come
and if he can replicate that why not
ninety-five point two races up to 17th
but with them what a few divers to come
well will you produce so down over that
standard you're going to be absolutely
devastated if you don't make the cut
Sebastian via in Colombia
well he's gonna struggle to make the cut
25th coming in to this fourth dive and
the feet just roll over not not badly so
max of seven coming to us via the PA and
perhaps you can hear them too the
calculation is done and he's at other
77.7 next up David Boudia from the
United States 16 national titles a
distinguished career reverse three and a
half somersault well now he was eight
coming into this dive some consternation
there it's the vertical position was
certainly was not achieved through the
tucks early he's looking for the water
now and
and one fake just rolled over big splash
their head drops 44 5 5 that'll send him
into the trouble area I think you'll be
alright now comes the man setting all
the standards to bow the 19 year old
with a back three and a half somersault
piked let's just enjoy it
oh and enjoy it we do he's averaging 90
for his first three dives really gets
some power off the platform straight
into such a tight position pulls it
around saves it a little he seemed to be
a bit short coming to the water but then
he's got this ability to minimize the
splash and rip an entry even without
perfect position Finas world diver of
the year last year that's solid again
even when they don't reach the absolute
heights they never let their standards
drop 86.4 he's had two of those and two
dives in the 90s it just churned them
out nothing Sasha Klein from Germany has
had a good evening so far this is a back
three-and-a-half somersault very nice
in the pike position so it just presents
a different look for the judges to
consider here piked obviously when they
grab it behind the knees legs straight
out as opposed to be tucked when they're
up there in the ball five foot eight
there's a more powerful type of guy very
strongly through his dive they're not
only one eight two so he's had two
schools in the 90s with dives three and
four buddy
clap to 17th back two and a half
somersault one the half twist three
point two the Terry fair can't afford to
drop too far back it's a steady effort
such a distraction to him preceding a
British diver not disrespectful just
excited and seventh year for kept or
could have been a bit tighter in their
thighs to chest you'll still be
loitering around the bubble we think up
to it rather 10 meters platform is one
of the hot tickets three Olympic Games
and they were all pretty hot and they've
all turned out to see Tom Daley who won
the national under-18 title when he was
only ten forward for a half somersault
tucks three point seven
well the crowd liked it a little more
than the judges will I think he he was a
little at an angle on entry saved it
quite well in terms of the splash but
just check how vertical he was at the
moment he hit the water and he wasn't
quite there and the feet were just a
little split as well
well the nation loves him I think and an
eighty three to five for Tom that he's
certainly on that form for the semies on
Keala beanie twenty-eighth now has a
reverse three and a half somersault
three point three the tariff for the
Italian just towards the bottom of the
field so it needs something special here
just not as tight not as convincing not
taking up as good a position for the
last moment of the dive some of the more
experienced men toes need to be pointed
here they kind of got there towards the
end but they're just just some form
errors that the judges identify here and
he's not fully straightening for the
last moment and fifty four for five for
Andrea you'll stay in the bottom half
doesn't next up it's who got a Parisi
from Brazil there's olympic games for
him
semi-finals would represent progress but
back in 29th this arm stand back double
somersault two and a half twists needs
to be absolutely on the money
well looked to have a good position here
in the arm stand pushed away with good
strength twist four okay not too much
wrong with that dive except her for the
finish not leaving that good impression
for the judges but seventy five six
Peter Waterfield was the Commonwealth
Games gold medalist in Manchester said
the home cloud inspired him and he needs
a bit of that from these supporters now
to keep up the progress because the last
dive was a belter pulled out of 90 this
is a back three and a half somersault
tucks just the three point three terrace
well again one of those dives where the
athlete saves the entry even though they
weren't quite vertical and with a three
point three instead of a three point
seven difficulty which was the case of
his previous driver who can't hope to
score around 90 he didn't get to the
vertical minimal splash but not optimal
position he's still arching on his way
in
it's gonna give the crowd a difficult
evening because he's flirting with
qualification 18 remember we're looking
for from this evening who will be back
here at 10 o'clock in the morning a long
wait for this competition at the Olympic
Games right to the end before getting
underway and here is the standings after
four of six dives chuubo Sasha Klein
really impressive Lynn you a german
sanchez galperin to mexican divers Tom
Daley up to seventh now gradually
working his way up the field doing a bit
of a mo farah mainly working his way up
the field now this is the important cuts
David Boudia
more uncomfortable than he will have
flight young Jimmy Conner just
scrambling the right side of the line
but only were less than three points
ahead of you and Claire Aguilar and
Peter Waterfield is pulling up there and
trying to claw back the ground he lost
with those opening dives it's pretty
much halved the deficit he had after the
previous round he was some 18 to 20
points adrift of the cutoff and now he's
only nine behind so you know he's got
two dives left and can be done that's
for sure he's doing it the hard way
though I'm necessary pressure you think
they've galperin kicking us off again oh
dear he's just switched off well we said
it's a long night I caught one the diver
having a bit of a yawn in the recovery
pool a moment ago and this is just
terrible entries at completely the wrong
entry angle and a 3465 for galperin he
doesn't score that too often it was
ranked fifth so he stopped slack but
what device doing that tomorrow if he
makes the cut successfully enough Lynn
you a
from China arm stand back double
somersault two and a half twists worth
three point six and he is in third place
after four dives his dives of seventy
eighty ninety and a hundred in that
region from Guangdong province five foot
four eight zone five pretty perfect size
and shape map for a diver and again he's
done a nice job of retrieving the dive
at the end here the ankles lost each
other at the top but he found the water
well and didn't make much of a splash
and the judges want to give him high
AIT's just corkscrewing his way through
the air and into the water and a ninety
one point eight well a three point seven
difficulty certainly assists Victor
Ortega 16 right side of the line for the
Colombian and he should stay there too
that's a lovely dive from Ortega taken
swing when he was just three years of
age by his parents because he was
struggling with that and with asthma and
they felt the exercise would do him a
lot of good so another example they have
just how much a sporting lifestyle can
help your overall health providing you
can dive off a ten meter board of course
and Victor Tiger an 84 1/5 keeps himself
very much in contention to continue
Anton Zeck off with an arm stand back
triple somersault nice so he's fairly
comfortable
watch his Pike position in this one Lord
no I didn't like it he he wasn't very
straight with his legs and the hands go
to the faces of his little cheer squad
there and he was all over the place the
knees were bent initially got it to a
straight position then twisted and was
that less than a perfect angle coming in
and that'll hurt 47:25
but all know that if they do progress
through to tomorrow and then tomorrow
evening that a poor dive is just not on
if they have genuine ambitions of being
in contention for the medals
Timofey or de chick from Belarus he's
left himself too much to do ranked 29th
coming into this one see he controlled
that dive really well and but the better
bit of guys can just give that
impression for the judges with much less
splash than this he seems to hit the
water very vertically and then doesn't
control what happens after him he's
reached finals in the synchronised
events at World Championship level but
again finding it harder to make an
impact in the individual competition
he's young Keon Jewry from the
Democratic People's Republic of Korea 16
year old
well I know that's a big splash but
that's actually one of his better dives
in this competition for real and the
coach looks a little more pleased he's
had a difficult night
if the sport is to progress in these
countries then they have to take the
risk of bringing divers to this level of
competition getting that experience and
try and build that knowledge base and
it's experience too for the coaching
staff not just for the competitors the
whole team gains from the experience how
to prepare your athletes for competition
what to say to them before and
afterwards that's all a learning
experience for coaches as well as what
the athletes go through all these
individual athletes not just in the pool
but talk about the team behind them
Jimmy Connor from Australia the 17-year
old who is 18th right on the edge
reversed three and a half somersault
tucked which he has to get fairly right
so young these vulnerable moments
well a fairly nice job done with that
but as I just mentioned he is right on
the cusp and Jiang Ming Chen is his
coach quite a lot of Chinese coaches
working with the diving program in
Australia and he's getting sevens for
this you can see for yourself he's not
quite the entry he would have desired
you'll have to excuse our understandable
parental instincts coming in here
because these are young lads and you do
if you are a parent and millions out
there watching will be of course you've
got to empathize with what these young
lads are putting themselves through I
think you'd be pretty proud of all of
them if they're up there
Martin Wolfram at 20 a little bit more
mature he's eighth not doing too badly
at all back two and a half somersault
two and a half twists in there as well
three point six that one didn't quite
finish it off as he would have wanted
look good through the ear got all the
elements completed those ankles very
much together and again just that last
aspect judges it's interesting how they
set them up they can't see each other
they sort of a partition Golf four and
one side and three on the other he's
happy though is Martin and again we must
emphasize they don't get the front views
the top views the side views because you
can see them really maybe your ring or
not quite getting the the move right
through all dimensions they've got less
than two seconds to make the judgment
call young a Guerra who's 19th and still
fighting to stay in the competition that
reversed three and a half somersault
tucked that looked very good from here I
think he might just be giving himself a
bit of room to breathe
if that's a if that's an expression if
it wasn't that is now
breathing room might come out better but
that was a lovely entry from a grill it
should have done these calls no end of
good yeah eighty five point eight helps
when you're on the bubble and he knows
that he's he's pleased confidence to
take him to his last dive sure we're
gonna see some movement on the
leaderboard though with the sixth and
final Alexander bonder from Ukraine
twelfth reverse four-and-a-half
somersault tucked when he's good he's
very good banda ukraine wanted to get to
athletes to progress eighth in the world
championships at ten meters in shanghai
last year did get a little off the
square bond out but some hair on the way
down rescued it and does pulled an
eighty nine point one just had that one
bad died of his third was of 57
otherwise in the eighties ji-ho Park
from Korea he's 31st back two and a half
somersault one and a half twists just
needs to put in a nice clean dive to
give himself some encouragement and he
does that he's towards the bottom of the
field ranked 31st coming in to this
fifth dive and at this point competing
for pride as we often say it's something
in that studies and trains at the Korea
University of physical education in
Seoul
70 to his score they're very consistent
7.5 s run across Victor mini buy of that
view not for the queasy is it back three
and a half somersault panicked 32 foot
10 inches above the water in old money
back three and a half somersault hiked
three point six the degree of difficulty
well he looked so good through the air
that such a shame that he so spoiled it
with that finish many by have look at
the position he achieves here in Pike
it's those legs are so straight pulls
for the water now and just over they go
big splash and that'll hurt many behave
with a forty eight point six we'd like
to take that back or at least the last
bit no margin for error
well maybe a little bit tonight in terms
of qualifying but after that you've got
to get it right across the six dives if
you go to do yourself
justice German Sanchez has been fairly
close to doing that fourth in the
rankings to date this is his fifth dive
it's a reverse three and a half
somersault tucked one of his easier
dives in relative terms oh he does a
good job with it too I like him
German Sanchez I think we will see him
not just in the semi-final but the final
he's class spots the water goes in with
a minimum of fuss and in good position
he's in the flyweight division remember
at only 47 K
seven stone 680 4.15 and he's on his way
what about Riley McCormick 21 later this
month
the Canadian he is 14th verse three and
a half somersault
now they gain just a little sloppy at
the end for Riley who can't make any big
slip-ups he is only a few positions
inside the cut
and again over go the legs and this over
rotation at the finish the timing is
just so difficult to get spot-on world
championship finalist in Shanghai last
year so he will have definitely said his
stall out to be here tomorrow night let
alone tomorrow morning now he'd give him
ten out of ten for unpredictability
Matthew Mitchum defending champion and
this is an arm stand back triple
somersault and there is a lot of him to
get up level there
short he managed to minimize the damage
with the entry but he wasn't vertical
and were just gathering an impression or
at least I am that he's not the diver he
was four years ago he still loves being
on the olympic stage clearly with his
reaction but you see he's short there
he doesn't like personality it's just
form he seems to like yes certainly it's
not Talent we know that he's proved that
you just feel he's a bit of a natural
performer if he could just get himself
in the frame of mind get himself in the
final he's one of those guys that if he
has his day it's a good day
he was on my plane coming over from from
Sydney and at the airport that people
just couldn't get enough of me so
recognizable within Australian and such
a distraction for him I think at that
level they're shy Atomics really
wouldn't be quite right in diving it's a
it's a show-off sport isn't amazingly
and here's my vic of norway that's his
best entry so far giz mervich
first Norwegians qualified for the
Olympics remember since 1992 I think
what you say Rogers is a point worth
elaborating that some of the divers say
look our bodies are on display we're
very much on display you see all of us
our courage is also exposed and in that
sense it's no place for shrinking
violets it's a performance it's a show
it's the same with the gymnasts as well
you know you can see they get the
dismount right and a great smile and
they love the applause that's the divers
I wonder how much of the applause they
hear underwater feeling they sense it
Francesco Del Amo from Italy with a
reverse three and a half somersault
he's 21st not over for him yet mining
means he needs to get this three point
three difficulty correct and get some
points on the board and that's two
consecutive average dives from Del Amo
and and he was in contention to be in
the semi-final two dives ago and it's
just slipping away from him now
32 contestants so it's a big field it's
a long time between the dives but I
remember in the 3-meter springboard
which it's probably the most contested
category of having more than 50 divers
for a world championship and that is a
long long competition on a long wait
between dies sorry Christopher s Gilson
from Sweden where's he 23rd equal
well and he whatever is going wrong with
duomo is going wrong with SQL sin that
that's twice now but both men have had a
chance to make a statement late in the
competition about forcing their way into
the top 18 and they've just not
delivered this is a great shame they're
good enough but there's the pressure in
that intangible you got the platform you
got the pool and you got a very short
amount of time to get it right and it's
what's between the ears and what they
can sometimes be the differential Eric
Sain from Canada's first Olympic Games
while proving a tough test for him 28
phases are back three-and-a-half
somersault Canadians normally send quite
a strong team with quite a high sense of
ambition so I think he'll be feeling the
discomfort here back in 28th position
before these scores are added in I got
such a great tradition have an A in the
sport when look at the deputy Alexander
one of the Great's of all time really in
considering his longevity and success
they've got a couple of bronzes so far
in this Olympics so the team will be
feeling confident but he's just not
Haley's day has he now 49 five there for
Eric I think he'd like it to to be over
now
Ryan Nixon low-mass from Malaysia
who's 26 he has an inward
four-and-a-half somersault this is a
really difficult dive four point one ten
out of ten for ambition
oh and we'll give him high marks for
execution to the coaching staff are
happy could have just performed himself
into the next round here
la masse he's had a little bit of
inconsistency through his competition
this evening but a very difficult dive
done well the degree of difficulty is
really going to kick him up here smiles
all around he's won Commonwealth Games
medals and Asian Games medals so he's
used to performing and delivering a 96 a
good score and 36 is a good score I
can't change very dramatically can't it
gives you an idea of what lies ahead in
this competition when it really starts
to hot up over the next 24 hours this is
even Garcia in sixth place and he's got
a reverse three and a half somersault
tucked here
I'll be able to hear out
spanish-speaking colleagues next door
loving the Mexican performances underway
on board a lahar die just rolls off the
tongue it is a beautifully named places
no I feel like I got to go there just
because of Guadalajara famous World Cup
football venue it was in Mexico that's
where it's famous name in Britain and
Mexicans are showing that diving as well
as football is one of their strong
sports and they're having a good games
and an eighty five point eight for Ivan
he's looking pretty secure two silver
and a bronze for Mexico so far in these
games and he might fancy adding to that
if they're two divers really have a big
night Nick McCrory 10th position back
three and a half somersault for the
American bronze synchro medalist
well I was okay he's had his moments
tonight as well means that just be
steady here and make sure he finishes it
off
[Music]
well a top ten diver when he's informed
they're gonna be back in less than 12
hours so the schedulers have put them on
the spot of it I think seven o'clock
here in the UK started and it's not
going to finish till after ten o'clock
and then they're back at ten o'clock in
the morning time I get home and I might
need a massage and it is a tight
schedule isn't and I looked at it and
thought it's demanding on a number of
people on nowhere about us between a
cruise and staff and and of course the
athletes
gira he was in 22nd position with a
reverse three and a half somersault
there he'll be wanting to have a
difficult 12 hours
lots of aids coming in he's really got a
few places to make up though he's fifth
and six dives 79 point to 18th with some
to come though with this fifth dive
series
Sebastian veer now 20 year old Colombian
23rd his ranking back three-and-a-half
somersault which he delivers very
quickly he does and delivers well not
much of a splash from guys only some 54
kilos and 64 centimeters not a lot of
him finds the water good entry don't
think he's got a huge amount of
experience in this level of competition
World Championship or Olympic where it's
a different world and the divers must
find some of the performances of the top
competitors intimidating almost not
David Boudia who's up next though begin
you're giving a look at the good
camaraderie down on the pool deck
opposition coaches give some
congratulations athletes walking past
back three and a half somersault for
David Boudia who is 17th and just living
on the edge of it
[Applause]
those little imperfections we're seeing
from those below the top five has a
wonderful pike position stretches
reaches splashes so 7s 7 and a half's
the 8 will be discarded and an 81
difficulty helping him along there with
a 3.6 tariff she bowed out leading the
pack here for the 18 year old whoa how
does he do it we've bounced along that
board before I got it like as a spring
board almost yes it a real looping
approach if you like he's just very
light on his feet easy through the air
hits the water and not much of a splash
of making a few headlines and bow as
confirming his standing here with a 99.9
as we said he comes from a very poor
background he knows that Olympic success
will transform not only his life but
none of his family as well this is
special Kline who's doing very well
second place reverse straight 1/2
somersault there so he's trying to split
the two Chinese
champions Chu and Lin there's some 20
points difference between Chu and Lin
466 to 445 and see if such a client can
force his way in there very solid dive
89 126 this really good see him at his
absolute peak just staying in the zone I
think they call that
and he said world there isn't he'll in
the client just one point behind Liam
just couldn't sneak in ahead of him but
an 89 very nice dive great result
without even cap tour from Belarus
twenty five-year-old from Minsk 15th
back three-and-a-half somersault its to
keep it going
at four World Championships six European
Championships got the experience has he
got the points to keep it going
it hasn't got the finish there I'm
afraid they're not cheering that dive
they're cheering the next competitor
three point three was the tariff fair
they give us the names of the athletes
and some of the sheets we have they
usually put the last name first when I
see Thomas daily it's presented to me as
daily Thomas I nearly want to say Daley
Thompson though they're quite different
sports and quite different bills but
maybe a taste at the same success and
the great decathlete across to Thomas
Daley both have tremendous popularity
Tom Daley 18 years of age and getting
better as the competition progresses
back three and a half somersault three
point six the tariff and he is seventh
after a shaky start oh my goodness by
his standards that's a terrible ending
to that dive
3.6 degree of difficulty but well I
think he's embarrassed to come up he's
putting this home support right through
the mincer here isn't he
won't do the confidence of his teammates
at Peter Waterfield any good he's got to
come up with two very good dives to make
it to the semi and in the 39.6 sees him
tumbled to 1600 is the diver who set new
British record points totals this year
we're not seeing it this evening Andrea
she had a beanie now from Italy for
three and a half somersault and he's
just really diving for personal pride
back in 30th it's one of those young
divers who will gain enormous leap from
the opportunity to complete here it's
not possible if he scores now to be
progressed to the semi
just seventeen years of age we must
emphasize again
Hugo Parisi and then water-filled
that'll completely v dies Parisi is 28
this is a reverse three-and-a-half
somersault tucked he's in 27th position
the Brazilian nice dive I just wonder 28
whether he would be tempted to just hang
on for Rio in four years time and he'd
be in his thirties
it's possible stay injury-free this is
one of his better ones fairly good
vertical position for the entry from
Hugo Parisi toes have got a good grip on
the end of the platform they're acting
like hands really with the grip a little
bit of excitement at the end of every
series of dives because the last man up
is the very popular Brit Peter
Waterfield and he like Tom Daley is
making sure his many supporters have an
anxious night he too has been pulling
his way up the field but he too can not
afford to blow another dive or reverse
three and a half somersault he's in 20th
position and diving to make the cut bit
of a splash there wasn't there it's not
what he needed it should have been
tidier than that to just crawl back a
few more points and take some more
pressure off he's fourth dive was so
good he really did something about his
position but that splash means he can
only get sixes and six and a half
amazing range of dives if between four
and a half and seven at it that
there's some inconsistency now those two
scores come out but you don't want to be
seeing four and a half and seven as a
range they've got to be closer than that
well he's piled all the pressure himself
for the last dive but it's China 1 & 2
Sasha Cline the Germany and the two
Mexican divers and Germany having a good
good evening Martin Wolfram they're up
into sixth Matthew Mitchum 10th we
should at least see him again David
Boudia as well other big names glib gal
purina's slipped away a bit like Tom
Daley glib galperin had a very good
start Tom Daley that disastrous dive but
still him with a chance there's the cart
just behind James Connor hanging on by
his fingertips budding cap tour and
Brian Lomas the road the two divers most
in touch this is also where the program
you've organized and just where you've
put your bigger tariffs dives can really
make the big difference can't it whether
you've saved it for the end or put them
in mid competition proud of stayed with
it commendably all the way through the
competition got a feeling this is very
much the appetizer for the big one when
it starts tomorrow and into tomorrow
night water filled in 23rd position it's
tough to come back from the Alperin
started off like a train that come a
little bit off the rails in the latter
stages so he want to make sure he
finishes strongly with this back two and
a half somersault two and a half twist
with a three point six tariff
yes just to extend the analogy a bit
further it's a train that's running out
of steam I think it that entry angle was
seriously short of vertical he's got
great dives in him that he needs six
back-to-back to challenge the top view
he's got a very distinguished career
behind him but again those eight
operations on his back and knee missed
two years of diving done brilliantly to
get back but maybe he's just a finding
it a bit tougher to try and string a
whole series of dives together 81 points
there with seven and a half's the marks
that count he's got an anxious half hour
just to make sure he comes back again
you know back at the top of the ranking
or rough second top Lynne you a has
beaten queue the world champion at the
national trials in May so you know he's
not come here for silver but that is for
tomorrow of course back to a half
somersault two and a half twist he's
some 21 points behind his teammate the
finish of this dive not quite perfect
but a very tidy through the air there
are just beautiful gymnasts
not too much wrong with that he sort of
collapsed into that somersault beneath
the water and it's the crossover of the
ankles there the judges do well to see
that and 86.4 had an injury to his waist
over the last year or twos which is
unusual must be running cause stomach
muscles which come under such a lot of
strain
Victor Ortega from Colombia he's ninth
the verse three and a half somersault
just needs to keep it tidy if you're
wondering what that tattoo is on his
lower chest it's life that's what he
embraces give it everything and that's
part of his sort of personal philosophy
of how he approaches things
it's a very individual sport that seems
to attract individuals one of them
they're really strong characters with a
bit of an artistic side to their nature
because they like to see it as what
they're doing is being very creative is
it it takes a certain type of person to
want to jump off a three a 10 metre
platform until zakharov from the Ukraine
he's 14
back two and a half somersault two and a
half twist very tidy
it's this consistency been like over the
evening is that Grove coming in at 14th
before this dive and he's had a
near-disastrous 47 to fivers his fifth
dive at 70s 80s and now 86 for he's got
away with that that nightmare fifth dive
hasn't he really competitors who would
like to have the option of dropping
their worst dive a lot of their mulligan
not possible
Timofey called a chick from belarus down
in 29th reversed three and a half
somersault
he's his farewell dive
he's just not able to control his
entries makes a big splash dive after
dive and that's not even with a poor
position so he's gotta learn how that's
done there's a couple of tricks that
happen under the water and he hasn't
mastered after finishing tenth in the
world championships last year I think
he's going to get into bed tonight and
think that he's not really done himself
justice he owned Jewry from Democratic
People's Republic of Korea the 16 year
old almost on work experience here
really down in 32nd place he's finished
the competition well he's fifth dive was
one of his best and his last clearly his
best good you want to see them leave
feeling good about themselves and we
mentioned how much on display they are
and when you're this age and your ego is
a fragile thing see how they notice one
aspect of these Olympics that it's the
the highest level of competition but
away from that top there is a great
feeling of support from the crowds to
two competitors who are young or trying
to make their mark this is Jimmy Connor
here at 17 he's right on the bubble at
18th a lot of people in Australia family
and friends got their fingers crossed
for this next dive see if he can make it
through back two and a half somersault
one and a half twist
always done a fairly decent job of it
too so he's gonna have to be beaten he
hasn't played himself out of contention
he's put in a good dive and now the
cards let them fall how they may and
this is what you want to see everyone
putting together a good competition so
that if you get beaten by a better diver
that's okay but rather than you not
giving of your best I think it's the
drivers who've cut out the disasters who
will feel that at least they've put on
some sort of a show 60 7.2 and not with
a high tariff there so he's not been
able to get into the 70s and it may be
enough on those around him how they
respond
Martin Wolfram from Germany's had a good
evening
up in sixth forward four and a half
somersault powerful dive at 3.7 the
tariff
well he's been tardy all evening and
he's kept it going to the last and
something in the 90s here really
committed himself to that dive along the
platform didn't he oh he's he's happy
and justifiably he's improved he had to
in the 70s then two dives in the 80s
three in fact and then one in the 90s so
he's one to watch young Claire egg
wheeler twelfth back two and a half
somersault two and a half twist for the
Cuban age 22 and his second Olympic
Games
well that's a busy dive isn't it there's
a lot going on right there
three point six degree of difficulty
two and a half twists two and a half
somersaults it's just a blur of limbs
and torso spinning
well after he reached the semi-final in
Beijing he will be looking for at least
that four years on the mind is an
amazing thing that it can make the body
do that so quickly eighty four point six
a guidette
Alexander bond of became eight from the
synchro competition remember the 18 year
old Ukrainian back two and a half
somersault two and a half twist to
complete his program and he is in
seventh place
well now the solidarity's had up to here
he's had four good dives and one for one
and that's closer to good than poor I
think he'll have his sights set on being
here tomorrow night not just tomorrow
morning yes he not quite as clean
perhaps it's the Chinese with his leg
form and his the pike position he
briefly gets into here those knees were
bent 81 though that three point six
tariff and he's done enough I'm sure
ji-ho Park from career in Busan 28 arm
stand back double somersault 1/2 twists
and he's got to get up into that arm
stand position
it was a real effort getting away from a
platform wasn't it it was a little
microphone up there to catch any noises
coming from the divers and yeah just
another man gathering experience you
feel the arm strength needed to get some
height from that not just fall away into
the dive just collapse into it the top
exponents they are really pushing
pumping themselves away from the
platform yes he's not the most
powerfully built of the divers we have
here Pomona by ov back two and a half
somersault two and a half twist and he's
in 17th place with not much room to
spare 18 remember is the cutoff point
back two and a half somersault two and a
half twist
well if he was in trouble before he's
not now he for that the world slashed
here in Shanghai you look at that and
realize that he's he's got something
more in him and there it is
he's delivered and he'll be fine because
he's got the good score coming here
current European silver medalist so he's
a man with expectations to succeed and
perform when you see a dive like that
you wonder what what was he doing 17th
with one dive to come then that doesn't
help James Conner who's the man on the
cusp if you like as mini babe
sort of blows him away he was already in
front of him but only just
German sound cares from Mexico in fourth
place forward four and a half somersault
to finish up with and he's put down an
encouraging marker a Mexican
hmm a little sloppy from him we want to
put himself in danger though and he's
too high up the rankings to fall out of
the top 18 that this one was overdone
extra fourth rotation takes a little bit
of pulling out of and they're running
out of space to do it
66.6
secret handshake exchanged and on we go
Ronnie McCormick from Canada 13th place
back three and a half somersault didn't
make the final in Beijing he was 16th
and another man who I think is now safe
certainly couldn't afford a major
mistake sitting 13th but with this dive
we can count him in nicely executed
reaches for the water maybe not quite
vertical but he's got that skill of
minimizing the splash I'll be alright
86.4 yeah little sigh of relief there
I'm sure he must have known in his heart
he had a cover but he's still in the
hands of the judges aren't you Matthew
Mitchum defending champion 10th place
after 5 dives back two and a half
somersault two and a half twists well
it's the Australian going to come up
with this time
or one of his better ones and I think
we've just got another locked into the
top 18 he looked less than his best
early in the competition but he's
starting to find form he might tell us
later that he always had it under
control and he looked safely through the
Beijing champ I think he is the sort of
highly experienced competitor who knows
that he's just got to get himself
through this you know and it's not being
won tonight he's that's been a tad
unpredictable hmm eighty four point six
though we'll see him safely across the
line and into morning competition I'm
wound against my Vic from Norway
down in 24 finishes with an inward three
and a half somersault tucked very nice
he's
had a couple of good dives and a few not
really olympic-class but I like what
he's offered here at the end he's
pulling some good scores for it - maybe
just came in a little nervous at 21 and
so pretty good on the one meter
springboard so he's got a range of
skills across the disciplines him up now
with Francesco ill whoa mo from Italy
arm stand forward double somersault with
one twist
she's only worth three point one he's in
26th place just getting himself up into
that position
no it'sit's such a disappointing thing
because he's first three dives were so
good and now pardon the obvious panties
plummeted out of contention with just a
drop off in form that maybe comes from
confidence that the fourth dive was was
poor so was the fifth the sixth he had
little chance by this stage he was
almost dropping into that dive there the
top divers have really snapped
themselves still out of that arm stand
position sixty point four five four
Francesco
Christopher s Gilson from Sweden he's
27th forward four and a half somersault
to end
didn't quite reach that desired position
for the entry that's such a lot of some
ourselves to get through four and a half
of them 3.8 sees most difficult dive he
saves it neurologically for last but I'm
at I just wonder too if there isn't an
argument for putting them in a little
earlier when you know the competition's
gonna go for three hours plus rather
than trying to rely on keeping your
concentration and form and confidence
going over what amounts to a three hour
competition
Erik Sain from Canada now in 30th
position not had the best of nights in
verse three and a half somersault to
finish off
not a lot of elevation off the platform
is to rip through these somersaults but
does it does a good job really by the
time he reaches the water he's got it
under control and all that camera angle
is just frightening isn't it when you
see how close the head goes maybe it's a
bit like the view from the passenger
seat sometimes when it's it looks worse
from there than it does with you or the
actual driver but you shudder at the
thought if they just catch themselves we
wouldn't be the first at all but no
wonder they get injured
Brian Lomas back two and a half
somersault two and a half twist xx cam
he may be oh this is what this is one
for the calculator and the judge is it
and we'll wait for the tabulation to be
done at the end but he I think he's
improved his position here a little
that's a good dive from Brian so four
eights two of them rejected but eight
and a seven and a half and an eighty
four point six is that that's a much
bigger score and James Connor God for
his last dive he has dived in World
Championship finals so he will have come
in here hoping even Garcia of Mexico
fifth ranked forward two and a half
somersault three twists and he's had an
encouraging evening
didn't need his dive in this last series
to be anything too special and well
frankly it wasn't but he's got a lot of
room to play with the synchro silver
medalist remember and he might be one of
those divers who's looking to continue
to improve throughout the competition
and maybe mounter a metal challenge if
others don't deliver of their best the
high tariffs fear helping boost a score
to seventy nine point eight now Nick
McCrory back two and a half somersault
two and a half twists in eighth pretty
comfortable three point six the tariff
we just want to sign off nice and clean
and then head off for a night's rest
yeah that'll give him some confidence no
nightmares with his last dive now he's a
world top ten dry diver six that world's
last year clean nice entry tour man at
180 centimeters or 511 so there's a bit
more of him to get around and a bit more
of him to make a splash but he's got it
all under control
job darling general terms tonight for
Nick
good job as American coaches like to say
I think good job as a Garrett xxi back
to an off somersault two and a half
twists three point six needs to pull out
a bit of a blinder here which he does
give it himself an outside chance here
as they gear up Santiago de Cuba the
veteran in the field at 33 competed in
five World Championships a couple of
eight and a half's and a nine are gonna
count here for a big last effort of
ninety three point six and he's up to
16th mat for 33 year old Sebastian via
now from Colombia 22nd position finishes
with the reverse three and a half
somersault
he needs some really strong marks here
pulls it around it's the effort of
straightening up there left him bent at
the hips a little is too flexible
and so completes on one meter and
3-meter springboard up now to David who
died of a synchro bronze medalist from
what must seem like a long time ago
their bidding of last week
he's eleventh back two and a half
somersault two and a half twists to
complete his evenings work is such a
range of body types competing in this
platform event he's a big strong man
bear powerful shoulders the shoulders of
a gymnast
that's a splash he went may be pleased
you didn't see
he did start as a gymnast actually broke
a bone in his foot and felt that it was
just a bit burned out my gymnastics Oh
decided diving off ten meters was a more
comfortable way to go takes all sorts
that's a very demanding sport to stick
with David Boudia 17th position and
things looking shaky for James Conner
you'll be able to bring you the final 18
shortly chuubo the 19 year old the
favorite from chummy left back two and a
half somersault two and a half twist I
was just looking at this even mayic
actually need to do that last dive so
far a hit without doing it he would have
qualified in the top ten great thrust
away from the platform into his twists
and again what an entry in this form he
looks untouchable his arm movements
through that he's in one position for
the twist and down back behind to hold
up the pike and then out so much going
on as you've said before in so many
different parts of his body and in 97 -
he's at 299 s Sasha Klein from Germany
third after five dives back to a half
somersault two and a half twists again
looking to leave on a high
it wasn't his best dive there very
tempting to switch off when you're in
his position he's so firmly entrenched
in the top getting late local time did
after a 10:00 in the evening three hours
of competition tough on divers ever
thought for the judges as well that's a
lot of concentration going on my my real
sympathy though is with the competitors
because it's not easy to finish a
competition go back to the village and
get yourself to sleep within a couple of
hours of competing because you pumped
they've got a refuel they'll need to
take the right things on board and I
need some rest
I think the shed your links crazy I'm
just amazed about the short turnaround
I'd even cap tour from Belarus 19th just
on the outside looking in Reverse four
and a half somersault to save it I mean
if we finish work at five o'clock in the
afternoon we're not expected to be back
at work at five in the morning
and that's the Askia kept to it finishes
his evenings work now Tom Daly is up
next
that's why you can hear the crowds
it's just confirmed cap to us mark 64 35
and he can have a bit of a lie-in
tomorrow and it's not like they just
turn up at 10 o'clock in the morning
either they hear early to warm up here's
a big moment though massive cheer tal
afford to have another disaster 16th
after round 5 and really we've had all
sorts so far you can hear the feel the
crowd just willing one more strong dive
from their local hero there you go well
maybe I thought it'd have been early
because he's flipped the feet over but
the crowd certainly had their say he's
got just a bit to play with with the top
18 going through and he was sitting 16
they are willing him on he's everybody's
favorite son and they will all just love
him to do well it really is a sir it is
a supportive sound I feel not just a
pressure if he can see it like that he's
gonna make it
he's through ranked 15 and there's three
to come and we know a couple of them are
no chance so he is in to the semi-final
Thomas Daly maybe not quite the way he
was looking that will of course affect
his dive position tomorrow in the
batting order
Andreea Kiana beanie who's pretty out of
it
two and a half somersault one and a half
twists to end up what's not being his
greatest night but at 17 a key learning
experience in his sporting career and he
has finished off nicely here Roger this
is one of his better dives pressures off
that sometimes has a bit to do with it
when you know you can't progress the
weight comes off the shoulders nicely
done 75.2 so he's got it in him he'll be
back he stick salad and it keeps the
appetite and fancies a trip to Rio and
who wouldn't who go Parisi who knows all
about Rio where he is from Brasilia
25th back to 1/2 somersault two and a
half twist
and again has to bend at the hips and
that spoils the entry and creates that
big splash so Parisi not quite there
finishing towards the bottom of the
field some kind of a miracle needed for
the last dive for our last man making
sure the competition comes to a dramatic
conclusion
Peter walk field of Great Britain
massive cheer but he has got work to do
23rd he's got an Olympic silver medal
remember in synchro and he needs to draw
on all that experience and all that
talent now to be back tomorrow morning
big moment for a local lad born just
down the road just a little short and
punchy the water underneath the surface
and I don't know if it's enough he needs
around 440 in total
[Music]
he's been such a storming influence in
British diving for more than a decade
competing at World Championships right
back in 1997 but this may well prove a
trip too far and 23rd is his ranking he
couldn't pull the enormous score that he
needed and so but Dyer is the last man
in or that would have been quite a
sensation if he'd missed it's the
ranking the two chinese divers setting
the standard sasha Klein and Martin
Wolfram a good night for Germany and for
Mexico
Alexandre bond or Nick McCrory from
Ukraine and the United States
respectively Matthew Mitchum more to
come from him
Anton zakharov in Victor Millie by Tom
dailyvee a local hero in fifteenth glib
golfer in fading rather but showing he's
got ability these marks will not count
tomorrow they start again from scratch
David Boudia
Jose Guerra and Brian Lomas and Jimmy
Connor the two most disappointed men
really they just miss the cut they are
on standby I think but these divers can
just put it down to a massive Olympic
experience a long line of competition
here but I've got a feeling overall
Steve that it is an appetizer and the
top men although we've seen some
outstanding performances at the top end
are really just warming up and getting
into their stride I just felt the turbo
didn't have to dive as well as he did
but he's in doing so he's made a
statement he's some 31 points clear of
linear and then back to Klein so 563 for
Schubert go back to third 525 and that
is a massive amount to make up and there
were no weaknesses in turbos performance
so he looks good for the gold and for
China to continue their dominance he has
been beaten before to bow Tom Daley
famously did it in 2009
when the pressure did get to him but
he's a more experienced diver now and it
is that ability to just churn out these
top top-quality dives he's not yet
dazzled but I don't think he's been
under the pressure to really do
everything he can do he knows he's got
plenty spare but a great appetizer this
is a great event
and we're looking forward to just seeing
more great dives we don't care who they
come from because we're being richly
entertained here at the Aquatic Center
and it's dramatic stuff off the platform
and the wonderful skills and courage
that we're observing and we're looking
forward to more of it I think the divers
would go away some with encouragement
some knowing that I've got something to
learn from it some tonight knowing that
after all that build-up and all that
work it's been a bitterly disappointing
evening for them but at the top end
though we really have seen some quality
couvreux is a sight to behold when he's
in top form I still got a job to do
tomorrow twice over and we're looking
forward to bringing that to you
something quite exciting a very
difficult night ahead then for 18 divers
to get their rest get themselves
mentally prepared and be back at 10
o'clock tomorrow morning
[Applause]
[Music]